Here's the correct answer: Our smallest boundaries
هذه هي الإجابة الصحيحة: النطاق ذو أصغر حد، وهو نطاق C، يمثّل نطاق المتغيّر weight.
Weight is declared inside the code of our if-statement inside these curly braces;
weight معيّن داخل كود عبارة if، داخل هذين القوسين المتعرّجين،
and a pair of curly braces define the bounds of a scope.
وقوسان متعرجان يحددان حدود النطاق.
So because weight was declared inside these braces,
لذلك، لأن weight معيّن داخل هذين القوسين المتعرجين،
it can only be accessed inside the code inside this boundary.
فلا يمكن الوصول إليه سوى في الكود الموجود ضمن هذا الحد.
Scope B is a little too big.
أما النطاق B فهو أكبر مما يجب قليلاً.
It contains the if and the if test condition,
إنه يحتوي على عبارة if وحالة اختبار if،
which are outside of our curly braces.
وهما تقعان خارج القوسين المتعرّجين.
So if we tried to access weight and say this test condition, we wouldn't be able to.
لذا، إذا حاولنا الوصول إلى weight داخل حالة الاختبار هذه مثلاُ، فلن نتمكن من ذلك.
We'd get an error because it's outside of weight scope.
سنواجه خطأ لأنه يقع خارج نطاق weight.
Scope A is the biggest.
أما النطاق A فهو الأكبر.
It's a whole program and it includes code where weight cannot be accessed,
إنه برنامج كامل ويحتوي على كود لا يمكن الوصول إلى weight فيه،
just like scope B did.
كما في النطاق B.
It's outside of the curly braces where weight is declared,
إنه يقع خارج القوسين المتعرّجين الذين تم تعيين weight ضمنهما،
so it's outside of the scope; and actually,
فهو يقع خارج النطاق. وفي الواقع،
scope A is the scope of the boolean variable isRecyclable.
فإن النطاق A هو نطاق المتغيّر المنطقي isRecyclable.
IsRecyclable has the largest scope because it's outside of any curly braces.
isRecyclable لديه النطاق الأكبر لأنه يقع خارج أي أقواس متعرّجة.
And that means its scope is our whole program.
وهذا يعني أن نطاقه هو برنامجنا بأكمله.
So keep scope in mind whenever you declare and use variables.
لذا ضعوا النطاق في الحسبان دائماً عند تعيين المتغيّرات واستخدامها.